Demira Pasalic

Software Developer New York, NY

demira.codes@gmail.com +1 917 387 5890 LinkedIn Web GitHub

Agile front end software developer with experience in Python with Flask and JavaScript based programming and with 11 years experience in secondary music education and the medical field. Possess the ability to pick up new skills quickly through independent study and group collaboration. Experienced in client communication and project management in fast paced environments.

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Python3, HTML, CSS, SQL, JSON, Mongo

Libraries and Frameworks: ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJs, Django, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap **Databases and other:** PostgreSQL, MongoDB, JSON API, Git, Django Rest Frameworks

Interpersonal skills: Problem Solving, Adaptability, Collaboration, Critical Thinking, Communication, Creativity,

Attention to detail, Decision Making, Customer Service, Flexibility.

PROJECTS

Budget App "DDJ Budget Hub", Demo

- Engineered a robust back-end infrastructure from scratch, including the creation of a custom API to seamlessly handle data storage, retrieval, and updates for user budgets and expenses
- Implemented secure user authentication mechanisms to ensure protected access to the application, enhancing user data privacy and account security
- Designed and crafted an intuitive and interactive front-end interface in React, providing users with a seamless experience for inputting budgets and expenses, while also allowing them to effortlessly track and manage their financial activities.

"BioFit Pasta" Company Webpage, Independent Freelance Project Demo

- Designed and developed a robust e-commerce website for a pasta creating company using React, enabling seamless online product browsing, selection, and purchase with integrated payment processing and order placement functionality.
- Implemented a responsive design to ensure optimal user experience across various devices, enhancing accessibility and usability for customers.

"Visoko Wood", Independent Freelance Project <u>Demo</u>

- Implemented e-commerce functionality, enabling the company to expand its market reach and increase sales by providing a seamless online shopping experience for customers interested in unique, locally crafted wood products.
- Utilized web technologies such as Javascript, CSS, and HTML to create a responsive and mobile-friendly design, ensuring optimal user experience across various devices and contributing to the online visibility and accessibility of Visoko Wood's offerings.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Software Engineer Fellow

09/18/2023 - 12/14/2023

 Successfully completed over 500+ hours of expert led instruction in JavaScript,React,HTML,CSS,Python,Algorithms and hands on learning of the industries most in demand technologies

EMA System Software Manager, Reforma Dermatology, Dr. Tajes Patel

12/16/2020 - 06/30/2021

- Ensured seamless operation of the EMA system, overseeing maintenance tasks and troubleshooting to optimize system functionality.
- system reliability, enabling the doctor and medical staff to produce accurate medical notes and billing information for improved patient care and administrative efficiency.

EDUCATION

General Assembly-Software Engineering Immersive Harvard Computer Science CS50 Course SheCodes Code Academy Music Academy Sarajevo/Music Theory Certificate of completion 2023-2023 Certificate of completion 2021-2021 Certificate of completion 2021-2022 Bachelor's degree 2006-2009